Guide to the Samuel Bourne photographs, circa 1861-circa 1889 RL.00130
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
- Photographic prints, circa 1861-circa 1889; 1; 546 prints 21 boxes
  - Sanawur; general view from Kussowlie, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1142)
    Has German caption on page below print.
    Original negative number: 1142
  - Bolundshohur; Mrs. Lowe's House, circa 1865-1866; 8 3/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1145B)
    Original negative number: 1145B
  - Lucknow; The Dilkusha Palace, circa 1865-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 14, Print RL-00130-P-1149)
    Original negative number: 1149
  - Benares; General View From the Opposite Bank of the Ganges, circa 1866-1868; 7 1/2 x 12 3/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1165)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 41.
    Original negative number: 1165
  - Benares; The River and Bridge of Boats, from the Mosque, circa 1866-1868; 7 1/2 x 12 1/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1167)
    Original negative number: 1167
  - Benares; The Great Mosque of Arungzebe, and Adjoining Ghats, circa 1866-1868; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1168)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 42.
    Original negative number: 1168
  - Benares; Bathing Ghat, circa 1866-1868; 8 3/4 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1168A)
    Original negative number: 1168A
  - Benares; The Burning Ghat, circa 1866-1868; 8 3/4 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1169)
    Unmounted; some water damage has resulted in rippling of print.
    Original negative number: 1169
  - Benares; "Vishnu Pud" & other Temples near the Burning Ghat, circa 1866-1868; 9 1/4 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1170)
    Original negative number: 1170
  - Benares; Raja Jey Singh's Observatory, and Dasaswa Medh Ghat, circa 1866-1868; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1171)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 43.
    Original negative number: 1171
  - Benares; Beseshor Nath, or Golden Temple, circa 1866-1868; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1172)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 45.
    Original negative number: 1172
  - Benares; "Gyan Bapee", or Well of Knowledge, circa 1866-1868; 8 7/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-1173)
    Original negative number: 1173
    Mounted on board. Alternate title written showing in white on negative reads "Benares Gyan Bafi or Well of Knowledge." According to Bourne historian Hugh Rayner, the white lettering indicates a later printing by the studio. Unmounted.
  - Benares; "Gyan Bapee," or Well of Knowledge, circa 1866-1868; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1173-1)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 46.
  - Benares; "Gyan Bapee," or Well of Knowledge, circa 1866-1868; 11 1/4 x 8 1/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1173-2)
    Caption on mount: Benares; Gosain Temple. Negative number as given, 1173A, is in error.
  - Benares; Sumeree Temple at Ramnuggur, from the tank, circa 1866-1868; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1174)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 48. Caption on mount: Benares; Sumeree Temple at Ramnuggur
    Original negative number: 1174
  - Benares; Sumeree Temple at Ramnuggur, Showing Carvings on the Lower Portion, circa 1866-1868; 9 1/2 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1176)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 47. Caption on mount: Benares; Lower part of Sumeree Temple at Ramnuggur
    Original negative number: 1176
  - Benares; Ancient Bhuddist Tower at Sarnath, circa 1866-1868; 11 1/4 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1181)
    Original negative number: 1181
  - Benares; Geometrical figures carved on ancient Bhuddist Tower at Sarnath, circa 1866-1868; 9 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1183)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 57.
    Original negative number: 1183
  - Cawnpore; The Memorial Well, with the Cawnpore Church in the Distance, circa 1864-1866; 7 5/8 x 12 1/4 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1203)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 50.
    Original negative number: 1203
  - The Memorial Well, from the South, Embracing the large Elephant Creeper, circa 1864-1866; 7 3/4 x 12 1/2 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1204)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 51.
    Original negative number: 1204
  - The Memorial Well, Seen Through Trees from the South, circa 1864-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1205)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 52.
    Original negative number: 1205
  - Cawnpore; The Memorial Well, the Marble Statue, from the Entrance, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1206)
    Original negative number: 1206
  - Cawnpore; The Memorial Well from the Inside, circa 1864-1866; 11 5/8 x 9 3/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1207)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 53.
    Original negative number: 1207
  - Cawnpore; Suttee Chowra Ghat, the Scene of the Massacre, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/2 x 12 5/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1208)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 49.
    Original negative number: 1208
  - Agra; The Fort from the South West, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/2 x 12 1/2 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1217)
    Original negative number: 1217
  - Agra; The Fort, Ummer Singh Gate, with the Taj in the Distance, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/2 x 12 3/4 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1218)
    Original negative number: 1218
  - Agra; The Fort, Delhi Gate, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1219)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 6.
    Original negative number: 1219
  - Agra; The Fort, The Palace of Akbar (marble), circa 1864-1866; 8 7/8 x 10 7/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1220)
    Akbar's Palace, Agra Fort
    Original negative number: 1220
  - Agra; The Fort,the Palace of Akbar with the Taj in the Distance, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1221)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 7.
    Original negative number: 1221
  - Agra; The Fort, exterior of the Zenana, circa 1864-1866; 10 7/8 x 7 3/4 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1223)
    Caption on mount: "Plate 159, Sieben Jahre Indien."
    Original negative number: 1223
  - Agra; The Fort, interior of the Zenana, showing the Mosaic work, circa 1864-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 14 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1224)
    Original negative number: 1224
  - Agra; Fort, Interior of the Zenana Showing the Mosaic Work, Another View, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1225)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 10.
    Original negative number: 1225
  - Agra; Carved Stone Pillars in the Old Palace of Jehangir, circa 1864-1866; 11 3/4 x 9 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1226)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 56.
    Original negative number: 1226
  - Agra; Quadrangle of the Motee Musjid (Pearl Mosque), circa 1864-1866; 7 3/4 x 12 1/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1227)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 8.
    Original negative number: 1227
  - Agra; The Front of the Motee Musjid, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1228)
    Original negative number: 1228
  - Agra; Interior of the Motee Musjid, showing the marble Saracenic arches and pillars, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1229)
    Original negative number: 1229
  - Agra; Interior of the Motee Musjid, Showing the centre aisle, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1230)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 9.
    Original negative number: 1230
  - Agra; The Screen enclosing the Sarcophagi in the Interior of the Taj, circa 1864-1866; 11 1/8 x 8 1/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1231)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 5.
    Original negative number: 1231
  - Agra; The Mausoleum of Prince Etmad-Dowlah, from the Gate, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1232)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 12.
    Original negative number: 1232
  - Agra; The Mausoleum of Prince Etmad-Dowlah, the Marble Cupola, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1234)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 13.
    Original negative number: 1234
  - Secundra; The Entrance Gate from the Garden, circa 1864-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1247)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 23.
    Original negative number: 1247
  - Secundra; The Garden and Mausoleum from the Entrance Gate, circa 1864-1866; 7 5/8 x 12 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1248)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 24.
    Original negative number: 1248
  - Secundra; Extensive View from the top of the entrance Gate, imparting a good idea of the 'Plains of India', circa 1864-1866; 7 3/4 x 12 1/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1249)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 42.
    Original negative number: 1249
  - Secundra; The Mausoleum of Akbar, circa 1864-1866; 8 3/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1250)
    Original negative number: 1250
  - Secundra; The Mausoleum of Akbar, from an angle of the first terrace, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1251)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 25.
    Original negative number: 1251
  - Secundra; The Mausoleum of Akbar, the upper marble sarcophagus, circa 1864-1866; 8 1/2 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1252)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 26.
    Original negative number: 1252
  - Secundra; The Mausoleum of Akbar, from an angle of the first terrace, circa 1864-1866; 8 7/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1256)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 27.
    Original negative number: 1256
  - Secundra; The Mausoleum of Akbar, The upper marble Sarcophagus, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1257)
    Original negative number: 1257
  - Futtypore Sikri; General view of the Ruins (west side) from the foot of the hill, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/2 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1260)
    Original negative number: 1260
  - Futtypore Sikri; Interior of the Great Quadrangle, showing Sheik Selim Chisti's Tomb, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/4 x 12 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1261)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 16.
    Original negative number: 1261
  - Futtypore Sikri; Interior of the Great Quadrangle, showing the inner side of the Great Gate, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/2 x 12 1/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1262)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 41.
    Original negative number: 1262
  - Futtypore Sikri; The Great Gate, from the Village, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1263)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 15.
    Original negative number: 1263
  - Futtypore Sikri; The Great Gate, distant View from the South east, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1264)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 14.
    Original negative number: 1264
  - Futtypore Sikri; The Marble tomb of Sheik Selim Chisti, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1265)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 17.
    Original negative number: 1265
  - Futtypore Sikri; Two of the marbled screens in the tomb of Sheik Selim Chisti, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1266)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 18.
    Original negative number: 1266
  - Futtypore Sikri; The Mosque on the Western side of the Quadrangle, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1267)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 19.
    Original negative number: 1267
  - Futtypore Sikri; The Palace of Beerbul, circa 1864-1866; 8 1/2 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 6, Print RL-00130-P-1269)
    Original negative number: 1269
  - Futtypore Sikri; Remarkable Pillar in the centre of the Diwan-i-Kass, or Hall of Audience, circa 1864-1866; 11 3/8 x 9 1/4 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1271)
    Original negative number: 1271
  - Futtypore Sikri; View of the Ruins from the top of the Dewan-i-Kass, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1272)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 20.
    Original negative number: 1272
  - Futtypore Sikri; The Panch Mehal (Five Palaces), circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1274)
    Original negative number: 1274
  - Futtypore Sikri; Carved pillars in the Panch Mehal, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1275)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 21.
    Original negative number: 1275
  - Futtypore Sikri; The Elephant Tower, seen Through the Elephant Gate, near view, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1278)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 22.
    Original negative number: 1278
  - Bhurtpore; General View from an Elevation in the Fort, circa 1864-1866; 8 3/8 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1298)
    Original negative number: 1298
  - Bhurtpore; The Principal Gate of the Fort, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1299)
    Original negative number: 1299
  - Bindrabund; Ancient Hindoo Temple, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1305)
    Original negative number: 1305
  - Bindrabund; Group of modern Temples, built by Seth Luchnee Chund, circa 1864-1866; 7 3/8 x 12 3/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1307)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 29.
    Original negative number: 1307
  - Goverdhun; Palace and tank, built by Rajah Bulman Singh, of Bhurtpore, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1311)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 30.
    Original negative number: 1311
  - Goverdhun; Upper portion of the Palace, showing beautiful Stone carving, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1312)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 31.
    Original negative number: 1312
  - Deig; General View from the Fort, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/4 x 12 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1314)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 32. About three-quarters of the left-hand margin is torn away.
    Original negative number: 1314
  - Deig; The Fort, from the North West, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1315)
    Original negative number: 1315
  - Deig; The Gopal Bhowun (Palace) and Tank, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1316)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 33.
    Original negative number: 1316
  - Deig; The Gopal Bhowun (Palace) from the Garden, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1317)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 34.
    Original negative number: 1317
  - Deig; Interior of the Nundh Bhowun, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1318)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 28.
    Original negative number: 1318
  - Gwalior; The Fort, from the road to Morar, circa 1864-1866; 7 1/2 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1324)
    Not on dealer list but present in box.
    Original negative number: 1324
  - Gwalior; The Fort, the Palace and principal Entrance, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1326-1)
    Original negative number: 1326
  - Gwalior; The Fort, the Palace and principal Entrance, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 14, Print RL-00130-P-1326-2)
  - Gwalior; The Happy Valley, Bhuddist Figures cut in the rock, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 3/8 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1328)
    Original negative number: 1328
  - Gwalior; Ancient Brahminical Temple in the Fort, circa 1864; 9 1/8 x 11 inches (Box 23, Print RL-00130-P-1329)
    Original negative number: 1329
    Gwalior is a city in the state of Madhya Pradesh, northern India. Unmounted.
  - Gwalior; Ancient Brahminical Temple in the Fort, the Interior, circa 1864-1866; 11 1/4 x 9 1/4 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1331)
    Original negative number: 1331
  - Gwalior; Smaller Brahminical Temple in the Fort, circa 1864-1866; 10 3/4 x 9 1/4 inches (Box 12, Print RL-00130-P-1333)
    Original negative number: 1333
  - Gwalior; View from the Dak Bungalow, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1334)
    Original negative number: 1334
  - Buildings in the Lushkur. Gwalior, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1334C)
    Unmounted print. Title and negative number taken from caption lettered on print. This image does not appear in the currently known Bourne & Shepherd studio list.
    Original negative number: 1334C
  - Buildings in the Lushkur. Gwalior, circa 1864-1866; 8 1/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1334D)
    Title and negative number taken from caption lettered on print. This image does not appear in the currently known Bourne & Shepherd studio list.
    Original negative number: 1334D
  - Delhi; View of the City, from the Jumma Musjid, showing the Ridge, circa 1864-1866; 8 1/2 x 10 7/8 inches (Box 13, Print RL-00130-P-1345)
    Original negative number: 1345
  - Delhi; View of the City, from the Jumma Musjid looking South, circa 1864-1866; 8 3/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1346)
    Original negative number: 1346
  - Delhi; The Palace, from the South West, circa 1864-1866; 8 3/4 x 11 inches (Box 13, Print RL-00130-P-1348)
    Original negative number: 1348
  - Delhi; The Palace, Lahore Gate, circa 1864-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1349)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 36.
    Original negative number: 1349
  - Delhi; The Palace, Interior of the Dewan-i-Kass, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1350)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 37.
    Original negative number: 1350
  - Delhi; The Palace, the Motee Musjid (Pearl Mosque), circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1351)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 11.
    Original negative number: 1351
  - Delhi; The Jumma Musjid, from the North-East, circa 1864-1866; 8 3/4 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1353)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 39.
    Original negative number: 1353
  - Delhi; The Jumma Musjid, from the North, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1354)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 38.
    Original negative number: 1354
  - Delhi; The Jumma Musjid, the Mosque and Quadrangle, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1355)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 40.
    Original negative number: 1355
  - The Chandni-Chouk, principal Street in Delhi, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1356)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 35.
    Original negative number: 1356
  - Delhi; The Kashmir Gate, circa 1864-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1357)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 53.
    Original negative number: 1357
  - Delhi; The Church, circa 1864-1866; 7 5/8 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1358)
    Original negative number: 1358
  - Delhi; The "Lat," or Stone Pillar raised by Feroze Shah, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1359)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 47.
    Original negative number: 1359
  - The Purana Kila, old Fort of Delhi, circa 1864-1866; 8 3/8 x 10 7/8 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1360)
    Unmounted print. Number written in pencil on back, partially cropped out.
    Original negative number: 1360
  - Delhi; The Kila Kona Mosque, Afghan Period, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1361)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 48.
    Original negative number: 1361
  - Delhi; The Mausoleum of the Emperor Humaioon, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/8 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1362)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 46.
    Original negative number: 1362
  - View from the top of Humaioon's Tomb, showing the Ruins and Tombs of old Delhi, circa 1864-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1363)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 43.
    Original negative number: 1363
  - Delhi; The Tomb of Nizam-ood-deen, circa 1864-1866; 8 1/2 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1364)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 49.
    Original negative number: 1364
  - Delhi; The Tomb of Mirza Jehangir. This is a piece of beautiful Marble carving, circa 1864-1866; 9 3/8 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1365)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 44.
    Original negative number: 1365
  - Delhi; Interior of the Chousut Kamba, or 64-pillared Hall, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1366)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 50.
    Original negative number: 1366
  - Delhi; The Observatory of Rajah Jey Singh, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 7/8 inches (Box 3, Print RL-00130-P-1367)
    From Photograph Album 3: Western, Eastern, and South India, page 44.
    Original negative number: 1367
  - Delhi; The Mausoleum of Sufter Jung, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1368-1)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 45.
    Original negative number: 1368
  - Delhi; The Mausoleum of Sufter Jung, circa 1864-1866; 8 1/4 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 13, Print RL-00130-P-1368-2)
  - Delhi; The Kutub Minar and surrounding Ruins, from the East, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1369)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 51.
    Original negative number: 1369
  - Delhi; The Kutub Minar, with the Great Arch, from the West, circa 1864-1866; 8 5/8 x 11 1/8 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1370)
    Original negative number: 1370
  - Delhi; The Kutub Minar, showing the carving on the first gallery, circa 1864-1866; 11 5/8 x 9 1/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1371)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 52.
    Original negative number: 1371
  - Delhi; Colonnade of Hindoo Pillars at the Kutub Minar, East side, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/4 x 10 1/4 inches (Box 7, Print RL-00130-P-1373)
    Original negative number: 1373
  - Delhi; The Kutub Minar, Interior View of the Eastern Colonnade, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 1/2 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1374)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 60. Print caption reads "Delhi; Collonade of Hindoo Pillars, near Kootub," a title associated with 1373, but this image is different, and is numbered 1374.
    Original negative number: 1374
  - Delhi; The Kutub Minar, Great Arch and Iron Pillar, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 1/4 inches (Box 17, Print RL-00130-P-1376)
    Original negative number: 1376
  - Delhi; The Kutub Minar, general view of the Arches, circa 1864-1866; 9 x 11 5/8 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1377)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 54.
    Original negative number: 1377
  - Delhi; Tomb of Shums-ood-deen Altomsh, builder of the Kutub Minar, circa 1864-1866; 9 1/2 x 11 3/4 inches (Box 2, Print RL-00130-P-1379)
    From Photograph Album 2: Northern India, page 59.
    Original negative number: 1379